http://www.careerstep.com/privacy-policy

chevron_right
Why CareerStep?
Last updated December 12, 2018
CAREERSTEP is committed to protecting your privacy when you visit our website. To demonstrate our commitment to user privacy, we provide the following information describing the information we collect and store, how we might use that information, security measures to protect that information, and your rights regarding the way we collect and use that information. This Privacy Policy applies to the online collection of information at CAREERSTEP’s website only. CAREERSTEP reserves the right to amend or otherwise modify this Privacy Policy at any time. As such, you are encouraged to review this Privacy Policy from time to time for any changes. If a significant change is made, Career Step will give additional notice.
COLLECTION AND STORAGE
CAREERSTEP collects and stores a variety of information from its website visitors. Some of this data is not personally identifiable and is collected and stored automatically via the use of cookies. A cookie is a small file that is stored on your computer’s hard drive and may contain the following information:
Your browser
Your Internet domain
Your computer's operating system
The links you followed to enter and leave our website
Your IP Address
This information lets us see how users are finding our website and tells us which pages are visited most often. Cookies may also be used to recognize you and give you access to specific areas of our website. You can opt out of the use of cookies by having your browser disable cookies or warn you before accepting a cookie, although doing so may impact your user experience. For more information on cookies, including how you can delete or reject cookies, please refer to your web browser help file.
CAREERSTEP collects and stores in our database certain personal information provided when you request information from us, communicate with us, or sign up in one of our courses. This information may include without limitation: name, address, email address, birth date, phone number, customer ID, social security number, prior education, course progress, scores, completion status, financial status. In addition we may collect your credit card number in order to process your sign up and collect payment.
We do not ever knowingly collect information from children under the age of thirteen, nor is our website designed to provide any service to children under the age of thirteen. If you are under thirteen, please do not give us any personal information. If you have reason to believe that a child has provided personal information to us, please contact us and we will attempt to remove that information from our databases.
USE OF INFORMATION
Non-personally identifiable information is used to help us improve our website by enabling us to discover and address the needs of our website visitors. This includes making our website accessible to the various web browsers and operating systems used to access our website.
CAREERSTEP may use third parties, including Google, to show you CareerStep ads when you visit different sites on the internet.
These third parties use cookies to collect non-personal information and show ads based on your prior visits to the CareerStep website.
You can opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt out page or you can opt out of the use of cookies generally by having your browser disable cookies or warn you before accepting a cookie.
However, opting out of Google's use of cookies or the use of cookies generally may impact your user experience.
For more information on cookies, including how you can delete or reject cookies, please refer to your web browser help file.
By supplying your contact information when requesting information or signing up in one of our courses, you authorize CAREERSTEP and its agents (outsource calls centers and academic partners) to contact you (using the information you provide to us) about CAREERSTEP or its agent's products and services, including product releases and updates, seminars, events, surveys, trainings, and special offers.
You can opt-out of future communications from CareerStep by sending an email to info@careerstep.com or calling 1-800-246-7837.
Unless expressly prohibited by a learner in writing, in furtherance of certain training and job placement objectives, CAREERSTEP reserves the right to release learner's email addresses to certain third parties in order for the learner to request special training software included with program and share learner information on an as needed basis as follows:
TYPE OF INFORMATION:
AVAILABLE TO:
Program progress, completion status and scores
Employer; Potential employer with whom a learner has applied; Sponsor paying all or part of learner fees; Third party resolution agencies; Third party organization through whom a learner has signed up with CAREERSTEP
Financial status (fee balance)
Sponsor paying all or part of learner fees
From time to time, CAREERSTEP may be required to provide personal information in response to a valid court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law. Unless prevented by law, CAREERSTEP will attempt to notify the learner involved prior to any release of such information.
This Privacy Policy does not apply to third parties with whom you may become involved in the process of training with CAREERSTEP or in the process of seeking employment. You are advised and encouraged to obtain applicable privacy policies of such third parties in order to know how they collect and use private information.
SECURITY
CAREERSTEP website(s) have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We utilize industry standard SSL encryption when accepting your credit card information during the online sign up process.
LEARNER RIGHTS
CAREERSTEP wants your information to be accurate and complete and recognizes that access and comment is necessary. You will not have the ability to change information on file, but may request a review or correction by either calling 800-246-7837 or emailing CAREERSTEP at privacy@careerstep.com.
You may also request that CAREERSTEP not disclose your personal contact information to third parties.
